Guide to the Dr. Robert C. and Claire McClenney Grieve Papers 1912-1983
Whitworth University Archives
Alumni Biography - Dr. Robert C. and Claire McClenney Grieve
1912-1983
1929-1941
Whitworth University Archives 300 W. Hawthorne Road Spokane, WA 99251 (509) 777-1000 http://www.whitworth.edu/library/archives/index.htm
General Collection J-15-GR
(Cu. Ft.) 1 Condition: Fair; Some Material in Tatters
Historical material belonging to Robert and Claire Grieve, Whitworth students of 1931-1933. Included are letters, flag strafed by Italian military planes, and other artifacts from missionary work in the Sudan.
Biographical Note
Whitworth College played an important part in the lives of Robert C. Grieve and his wife Claire McClenney who were students from 1931 to 1933. The pair married in June of 1936 and finished formal education in 1939 (At that time graduation from Whitworth was not a prerequisite for medical school enrollment at the University of Oregon).
They served under the Sudan Interior Mission from February 1940 until they were killed on August 23, 1940 by Italian air force strafing of their village.
This file contains letters, documents, the American flag shredded by shrapnel and bullets, and other artifacts from the Sudan. (Taken from a letter from H. Glen Ellison, Class of 1949, to Janet Hauck, Whitworth College Archivist).
Rights Transferred: All
Eleanor Grieve Ellison, 312 W. Hastings Rd., Apt. 604, Spokane, WA 99218-3715, (509) 464-1941
Dr. Robert Grieve; Claire McClenney Grieve
Sudan Interior Mission; Whitworth College, Spokane
Doro, Sudan
Colleges and Universities; Religion; Spokane; Washington (State)
- Introduction and Inventory (Box-folio 1/1)
- Portraits and Other Pictures (Box-folio 1/2)
- Photo Album and Scrapbook No. 1, circa 1932 (Box-folio 1/3)
- Photo Album and Scrapbook No. 2, 1929-1932 (Box-folio 1/4)
- Photo Album and Scrapbook No. 3, 1933 (Box-folio 1/5)
- Photo Album and Scrapbook No. 4, 1933-1934 (Box-folio 1/6)
- Scrapbook re Demise in the Sudan, 1935-1983 (Box-folio 1/7)
- Memorial Service and Other Memorials, September 22, 1940 (Box-folio 1/8)
- Grieve Memorial Organ at Whitworth College, June 6, 1943 (Box-folio 1/9)
- Condolence Cards, September 1943-October 1943 (Box-folio 1/10)
- Letters of Condolence, August 1940-October 1940 (Box-folio 1/11)
- Copies of Letters and Papers, 1935-1941 (Box-folio 1/12)
- Artifacts, October 10, 1935-1938 (Box:oversize 2)
  American Flag with Shrapnel and Bullet Holes, Map of Northeast Africa from the San Francisco Examiner, University of Oregon Medical School Diploma, Bible and Camera Rhinoceros Hide Whip, Miscellaneous Small Items.